ksb.com 2015-12-28

# KSB - Legal Information - Privacy Statement

## Storage of Access Data

Every time a user accesses a page on the KSB web site or opens a file, this access data is stored automatically in a log file on our server.

Each data record for a request consists of the following general information:

  * Original link from which the request originated
  * Name of the file
  * Date and time of the request
  * Volume of data transferred
  * Access status (file transferred, file not found, etc.)•
  * Result of the Web browser type query
  * IP address of the requester

The stored data is used exclusively for statistical purposes and is not made available to or shared with third parties, either for commercial or non-commercial purposes.

## Collection of personal information

Personal information is collected only when users provide this information themselves, for example in the course of registration, when completing forms or when ordering information material. KSB uses this information to respond to enquiries or requests and to provide users with information on the company's products, services or offerings in general. Personal information is not made available to or shared with third parties, either for commercial nor non-commercial purposes.

Users have the right to receive free of charge information about the personal information stored about them on request. They are also entitled by law to have their personal information corrected, locked, or deleted.

## Security

KSB uses appropriate state-of-the-art technical security policies and procedures to protect the data and information provided from unintentional or intentional manipulation, loss, damage or unauthorised access. When personal information is collected and processed, the information is encrypted for data transmission.

## Links to Other Web Sites

Our online offering contains links to other web sites. We have no control over whether the operators of other web sites observe the relevant data privacy and protection regulations.

As a provider of its own content, KSB is legally responsible for such content. A distinction must be made between links to content from other providers and content provided by KSB. KSB is not responsible for and does not own external content that is provided in the form of links and expressly identified as such. The provider of the linked web site is solely liable for illegal, incorrect or incomplete content as well as for any damage caused by the use or disuse of the information provided. The editor is only responsible for third-party links if the editor is positively aware of such links, including illegal content or content liable to prosecution, and if it is technically feasible and reasonable to prevent their use.
